<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>Hauts' Enterprise: More Permits</name>
    <author>Hautarche</author>
    <packageId>Hautarche.HautsPermits</packageId>
    <supportedVersions>
		<li>1.5</li>
		<li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
	<description>An ancient, star-faring enterprise has arrived on the Rim, offering their vast resources to those who will carry out their missions. Complete quests with each "Branch" faction to earn a wide variety of permits. While some simply drop items or summon shuttles, others can change NPC behavior, reveal world sites, deploy defensive structures, alter the climate, summon permanent pawns, enhance items, or even augment or introduce new ideoligions.

The Ideology, Biotech, and Anomaly DLCs enable additional permits and unique Branch factions. The Odyssey DLC lets you fight the Branch factions in space to obtain powerful, exclusive rewards and a new way to use permits.

Also includes the "Cosmopolitan" meme, which enhances cooperation between factions.

Use the mod settings to adjust the difficulty and reward of interacting with Branch factions to your liking. You can change how frequently they offer quests and how rewarding each quest is; if you want more challenge, you can even enable goodwill penalties for refusing or failing Branch quests, as well as set when those penalties should start occurring.

See the full description here: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1dAuUNcurXNYDNEptkQ9lHra1ZD-20gXyt8iQzq1KTIA/edit?usp=sharing
    </description>
	<modIconPath IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">UI/HautsLogo_Draft0</modIconPath>
	<modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
		<li>
			<packageId>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</packageId>
			<displayName>Royalty</displayName>
		</li>
		<li>
			<packageId>Hautarche.HautsFramework</packageId>
			<displayName>Hauts Framework</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3422815711</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1a22eD9tPS-IScSWPuz1Qw1RCMErd0fcZ?usp=drive_link</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
		<li>Hautarche.HautsFramework</li>
	</loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>